Planned Parenthood League of Massachusetts, 1859-2002 (bulk 1916-1960)
Sophia Smith Collection
- SERIES IV. RELATED ORGANIZATIONS
  - Miscellaneous organizations, [see also SERIES VII. RESOURCE FILES - Organizations]
    - Birth Control Clinical Research Bureau
      - Committee on Public Progressundated (Box 70, Folder 1)
      - Conference on Contraceptive Research and Clinical Practice 1936 (Box 70, Folder 2)
      - "Why Let Them Die" (typescript) 1938, [see also SERIES IX.OVERSIZE MATERIALS - Sound recordings] (Box 70, Folder 3)
      - Miscellaneous 1936-38 (Box 70, Folder 4)
    - Citizen's Committee for Planned Parenthood 1938-39 (Box 70, Folder 5)
    - Human Betterment Association 1955-62, undated (Box 70, Folder 6)
    - International Planned Parenthood Federation 1952-68, undated (Box 70, Folder 7)
    - Margaret Sanger Research Bureau
      - Campbell, Lorraine: correspondence, notes, and miscellaneous materials 1953-57, undated (Box 70, Folder 8)
      - Printed materials 1952-55 (Box 70, Folder 9)
      - Reports
        - "Possible relation of subnormal semen to the incidence of developmental anomalies in the offspring" 1964 (Box 70, Folder 10)
        - Severson Report 1958 (Box 70, Folder 11)
    - Massachusetts Central Health Council 1945 (Box 70, Folder 12)
    - National Committee for Planned Parenthood 1941, undated (Box 70, Folder 13)
    - National Committee on Federal Legislation for Birth Control 1929-37, undated (Box 70, Folder 14)
    - Voluntary Parenthood League 1918-24, undated (Box 70, Folder 15)
- SERIES V. CONFERENCE FILES, [see also SERIES IV. RELATED ORGANIZATIONS - Birth Control Federation of America/PPFA - Conferences]
  - Planned Parenthood League of Massachusetts (Box 70)
    - Community Leaders Conference on Birth Control (BCLM) 1938 (Box 71, Folder 1)
    - New England Conference on Birth Control and the Community (BCLM) 1936 (Box 71, Folder 2)
    - New England Conference on Tomorrow's Children
      - Correspondence
        - Advisory Board 1940-42 (Box 71, Folder 3-7)
        - Forbes, A.W. 1941-42 (Box 71, Folder 8)
        - National associations 1940 (Box 71, Folder 9)
        - Zimmerman, Carl 1940-41 (Box 71, Folder 10)
      - Cooperating organizations
        - National Conference on Family Relations 1940-41 (Box 71, Folder 11-12)
        - National Council of Parent Education 1941 (Box 72, Folder 1)
        - Miscellaneous 1940-42 (Box 72, Folder 2-4)
        - Miscellaneous 1940-42 (Box 72, Folder 2-4)
      - Film
        - Correspondence 1940-42 (Box 72, Folder 5-7)
        - Miscellaneousundated (Box 72, Folder 8)
      - Honorary Chairman 1941 (Box 72, Folder 9)
      - Literature tables 1941-42, undated (Box 72, Folder 10-11)
      - Papers
        - Lists 1941-42 (Box 72, Folder 12)
        - Requests
          - Correspondence 1941-42 (Box 72, Folder 13)
          - Order blanks 1942 (Box 72, Folder 14)
        - Texts 1940-42 (Box 73, Folder 1-3)
      - Planning and arrangements
        - Arrangements: correspondence 1940-42 (Box 73, Folder 4-5)
        - Planning Committee: correspondence 1940-41 (Box 73, Folder 6-7)
        - Registration, finances, and miscellaneous 1940-41 (Box 73, Folder 8)
      - Proceedings
        - Correspondence 1940-41 (Box 74, Folder 1)
        - Funding for printing 1940-41 (Box 74, Folder 2)
        - Requests 1940-41 (Box 74, Folder 3)
      - Programs
        - Planning 1942 (Box 74, Folder 4)
        - Requests 1940-42 (Box 74, Folder 5-7)
        - Printed 1940-41 (Box 74, Folder 8)
      - Publicity
        - Press releases 1940-42 (Box 74, Folder 9-10)
        - Miscellaneous 1940 (Box 74, Folder 11)
      - Speakers: correspondence
        - Invitations 1941 (Box 74, Folder 12)
        - Regrets 1940-41 (Box 74, Folder 13-15)
        - Miscellaneous
          - By date 1940-42 (Box 75, Folder 1-4)
          - By person 1941 (Box 75, Folder 5-7)
    - Population Problems In A Free World (PPLM) 1946 (Box 75, Folder 8)
    - Two State Legislative Conference (MMHC) 1940 (Box 75, Folder 9)
  - Other conferences
    - American Conference on Birth Control (National Committee on Federal Legislation for Birth Control) 1934 (Box 76, Folder 1)
    - Conference on Better Care for Mothers and Babies (U.S. Department of Labor, Children's Bureau) 1938 (Box 76, Folder 2)
    - Conference on Recreation and the Use of Leisure Time in Relation To Family Life 1937 (Box 76, Folder 3)
    - Conference on World Population Problems and Birth Control (New York Academy of Sciences) 1951 (Box 76, Folder 4)
    - National Conference on Family Life 1948 (Box 76, Folder 5)
    - Summer Institute for Social Progress. Roundtable on Birth Control 1935 (Box 76, Folder 6)
    - Trends and Resources in Family Living (National Conference on Family Relations) 1940 (Box 76, Folder 7)
    - White House Conference on Child Health and Protectionundated (Box 76, Folder 8)
    - White House Conference on Children in a Democracy (U.S. Department of Labor)
      - Reports and printed material 1940 (Box 76, Folder 9)
      - National Citizens Committee, follow up program 1943 (Box 76, Folder 10)
    - White House Conference on Children and Youth 1960 (Box 76, Folder 11)
    - White House Conference on Health 1965 (Box 76, Folder 12)
    - Miscellaneous 1929-67 (Box 76, Folder 13)
- SERIES VI. LEGISLATIVE FILES
  - History and background
    - "Birth Control and the Massachusetts Law"
      - Drafts 1941-50 (Box 77, Folder 1)
      - Drafts and final version 1951-59 (Box 77, Folder 2)
      - Correspondence, memoranda, and miscellaneous material 1946-59, undated (Box 77, Folder 3)
    - Birth control commissions 1935, 1938 (Box 77, Folder 4)
    - History of attempts to change Massachusetts birth control law 1959 (Box 77, Folder 5)
    - U.S. Legislature and "Birth Control in the Courts" 1936-42 (Box 77, Folder 6)
    - Test case research
      - Articles and notes 1929-38, undated (Box 77, Folder 7)
      - Correspondence 1938-48, undated (Box 77, Folder 8-13)
    - Cases
      - Brookline and Salem Clinics raid, [see also SERIES III. CENTRAL ADMINISTRATIVE FILES - Mother's Health Office - Clinics and SERIES VIII. CLIPPINGS AND ARTICLES]
        - Meeting records, reports, notes, and memos 1937-38, undated (Box 78, Folder 1)
        - Trial transcript 1937 (Box 78, Folder 2)
      - Corbett, Lewis 1937-40 (Box 78, Folder 3)
      - Gardner, Caroline T. et al.
        - Briefs 1938 (Box 78, Folder 4)
        - Court findings 1937 (Box 78, Folder 5)
        - Notes, correspondence, and background material 1937-38, n. d. (Box 78, Folder 6)
        - Supreme Court's dismissal 1938 (Box 78, Folder 7)
        - Trial transcript 1937 (Box 78, Folder 8)
      - Konikow, Antoinette 1928 (Box 78, Folder 9)
      - Miscellaneous legal opinions 1934-37 (Box 78, Folder 10)
    - Hospitals' dismissal of doctors
      - Connecticut 1947-49 (Box 78, Folder 11)
      - Massachusetts
        - Farren Hospital 1948-54 (Box 78, Folder 12)
        - Miscellaneous 1943-49, undated (Box 78, Folder 13)
      - New York
        - Poughkeepsie 1952 (Box 78, Folder 14)
        - New York City 1958 (Box 78, Folder 15)
        - Committee on Public Health 1931 (Box 78, Folder 17)
    - Legislation
      - Hearings
        - Doctor's Bill 1939-39, undated (Box 79, Folder 1)
        - Miscellaneous 1931-34 (Box 79, Folder 2)
      - House and Senate Bills
        - House Bill # 2035 (Initiative Petition to Allow Physicians to Provide Medical Contraceptive Care to Married Persons for the Protection of Life or Health)
          - Hearings 1941 (Box 79, Folder 3-4)
          - Statements 1941 (Box 79, Folder 5)
          - Miscellaneous 1930-52, undated (Box 79, Folder 6)
        - Cummins-Vaile Bill 1924 (Box 79, Folder 7)
        - Sheppard-Towner Act 1928 (Box 79, Folder 8)
        - Miscellaneous 1943, undated (Box 80, Folder 1)
      - Laws
        - Birth Control
          - Massachusetts 1921-64, undated (Box 80, Folder 2)
          - Other states 1925-65, undated (Box 80, Folder 3)
        - Clinics and dispensaries 1942 (Box 80, Folder 4)
        - Elections and political action 1940-47, undated (Box 80, Folder 5)
        - Food and drugs 1939-42 (Box 80, Folder 6)
        - Initiative petitions and referendums 1941-42 (Box 80, Folder 7)
        - U.S. Mail 1950 (Box 80, Folder 8)
      - Legal opinions 1917-39, undated (Box 80, Folder 9)
      - Other states and international
        - Cases
          - Bourne, England 1938 (Box 80, Folder 10)
          - Canada 1935-37 (Box 80, Folder 11)
          - Consumer's Union vs. Postmaster [NYC] 1944 (Box 80, Folder 12)
          - Mueller vs. Oregon 1941 (Box 80, Folder 13)
          - New Jersey vs. Kinney Building Drug Stores 1959 (Box 80, Folder 14)
          - PPFA vs. Rhythmeter Co 1948 (Box 80, Folder 15)
          - Puerto Rico 1939 (Box 80, Folder 16)
          - U.S. vs. One Package (Hannah Stone) 1936 (Box 80, Folder 17)
          - Young Rubber Corp. vs. C.I. Lee Co., Inc. 1930 (Box 80, Folder 18)
  - Initiative and Referendum Campaign
    - Field files
      - Counties
        - Barnstable 1939-53, undated (Box 80, Folder 19)
        - Berkshire 1939-40, undated (Box 80, Folder 20)
        - Bristol
          - Easton Survey 1955 (Box 80, Folder 21)
          - Miscellaneous 1941-52, undated (Box 80, Folder 22)
        - Dukes 1947-48 (Box 81, Folder 1)
        - Essex
          - Amesbury - Hamilton 1939-52, undated (Box 81, Folder 2)
          - Ipswich - Methuen 1939-52 (Box 81, Folder 3)
          - Nahant - Peabody 1946-48 (Box 81, Folder 4)
          - Rockport - Wenham 1943-52 (Box 81, Folder 5)
        - Franklin 1940 (Box 81, Folder 6)
        - Hampden 1940-41, undated (Box 81, Folder 7)
        - Hampshireundated (Box 81, Folder 8)
        - Middlesex
          - Arlington - Framingham 1940, undated (Box 81, Folder 9)
          - Newton, West Newton 1946-55, undated (Box 81, Folder 10)
          - North Reading - Shirley 1940-51, undated (Box 81, Folder 11)
          - Somerville - Tyngsboro 1940-52, undated (Box 81, Folder 12)
          - Wakefield - Woburn 1939-51, undated (Box 81, Folder 13)
        - Nantucket 1946-52, undated (Box 81, Folder 14)
        - Norfolk
          - Bellingham- Cohasset 1940-52, undated (Box 82, Folder 1)
          - Dedham - Milton 1946-53, undated (Box 82, Folder 2)
          - Needham-Wrentham 1940-53, undated (Box 82, Folder 3)
          - Wellesley 1940-53, undated (Box 82, Folder 4)
        - Plymouth
          - Bridgewater - Whitman 1939-52, undated (Box 82, Folder 5)
          - Brockton 1940-48, undated (Box 82, Folder 6)
        - Suffolk
          - Boston 1938-52, undated (Box 82, Folder 7)
          - Brighton - Roxbury 1940-53 (Box 82, Folder 8)
        - Worcester
          - Ashburnham- Dudley 1946-52, undated (Box 82, Folder 9)
          - Fitchburg
            - Correspondence with Emily Pescosolido (Ipswich, NH) 1945-48 (Box 82, Folder 10)
            - Miscellaneous 1937-53, undated (Box 82, Folder 11)
          - Gardner - Leominster 1945-53, undated (Box 83, Folder 1)
          - Lunenburg - Templeton 1946-50, undated (Box 83, Folder 2)
          - Upton - Winchendon 1946-53, undated (Box 83, Folder 3)
          - Worcester 1941-53, undated (Box 83, Folder 4)
      - Massachusetts, Western 1953 (Box 83, Folder 5)
      - Other countries 1940-50, undated (Box 83, Folder 6)
      - Out of state 1944-50 (Box 83, Folder 7)
      - Form letters 1949-52, undated (Box 83, Folder 8)
      - Programs and policy projects 1948-53, undated (Box 83, Folder 9)
      - Reports
        - Areas of greatest need
          - Boston
            - Census 1950 (Box 83, Folder 10)
            - Reports, addresses, and correspondence 1946-53, undated (Box 83, Folder 11)
            - Ward 9 data 1954-55, undated (Box 83, Folder 12)
          - Brockton - Holyoke 1943-53 (Box 84, Folder 1)
          - Lawrence - Newtonville 1943-53, undated (Box 84, Folder 2)
          - New Bedford 1937-53, undated (Box 84, Folder 3)
          - Quincy 1940-54, undated (Box 84, Folder 4)
          - Revere - Worcester 1947-54, undated (Box 84, Folder 5)
        - Miscellaneous 1940-53 (Box 84, Folder 6)
    - Initiative and Referendum Campaign, 1940-42
      - Ballot Law Commission vs. Karl Compton
        - Summary 1941 (Box 84, Folder 7)
        - Superior Court Briefs 1940 (Box 84, Folder 8)
        - Supreme Judicial Court Briefs 1942 (Box 84, Folder 9)
        - Findings 1942 (Box 85, Folder 1)
        - Hearings
          - Briefs 1942 (Box 85, Folder 2-6)
          - Summary and summons 1942 (Box 85, Folder 7)
      - Ballot wording 1942 (Box 85, Folder 8)
      - Budget 1941-42 (Box 85, Folder 9)
      - Campaign workers
        - Instructions and newsletters 1940-41 (Box 85, Folder 10)
        - Lists of names and addresses 1941 (Box 85, Folder 11)
      - Clippings 1942, [see also SERIES VIII. CLIPPINGS AND ARTICLES] (Box 85, Folder 12)
      - Contributors 1942 (Box 85, Folder 13)
      - Contacts 1938-42 (Box 85, Folder 14)
      - Correspondence, [see also SERIES III. CENTRAL ADMINISTRATIVE FILES - Massachusetts Mothers' Health Council - Referendum]
        - Cook, Frederic 1940-41 (Box 85, Folder 15)
        - Ely, Joseph B. 1940 (Box 85, Folder 16)
        - Form letters 1940-42 (Box 85, Folder 17)
      - Field reports 1940-42 (Box 85, Folder 18)
      - Initiative petition
        - Forms 1940-41 (Box 86, Folder 1)
        - Information for voters 1942 (Box 86, Folder 2)
      - Lawyers listsundated (Box 86, Folder 3)
      - Legislation
        - House Bill # 727 1943 (Box 86, Folder 4)
        - Legislative procedure 1939-40 (Box 86, Folder 5)
        - Legislative program 1941-42 (Box 86, Folder 6)
        - Public Health Committee hearings
          - Minutes and outline 1941-42 (Box 86, Folder 7)
          - Statement by Frederick Good 1942 (Box 86, Folder 8)
        - Senate Bill # 494 1941 (Box 86, Folder 9)
      - Opposition 1940-42, undated (Box 86, Folder 10)
      - Plans 1940-42, undated (Box 86, Folder 11)
      - Political Committees 1941-48 (Box 86, Folder 12)
      - Publicity, [see also SERIES III. CENTRAL ADMINISTRATIVE FILES - Birth Control League of Massachusetts - Committees - Mother's Health - Referendum]
        - Newsletters, [see Campaign workers - Instructions and newsletters] (Box 86)
        - Newspapers and magazines 1941-42, undated (Box 86, Folder 13)
        - Pamphlets and flyers 1940-42, undated (Box 86, Folder 14)
        - Press releases 1940-42, undated (Box 86, Folder 15)
        - Radio 1942 (Box 86, Folder 16)
      - Questionnaireundated (Box 86, Folder 17)
      - Reports and memoranda 1940-42 (Box 86, Folder 18)
      - Resolutions and statements 1940-42, undated (Box 86, Folder 19)
      - Signatures
        - Choices for the firstundated (Box 86, Folder 20)
        - Forms 1940 (Box 86, Folder 21)
        - Records 1940-42 (Box 86, Folder 22-23)
      - Speakers Bureau
        - Lists and outlines for speakers and topics 1940-42 (Box 87, Folder 1)
        - Speaker's kit 1942 (Box 87, Folder 2)
      - Supporters 1937-42, undated (Box 87, Folder 3)
      - Voting
        - Lawsundated (Box 87, Folder 4)
        - Records 1941-42 (Box 87, Folder 5)
    - Initiative and Referendum Campaign, 1947-48
      - Abortionundated (Box 87, Folder 6)
      - Addresses and mailing lists 1947 (Box 87, Folder 7)
      - Amendments (proposed) 1945-51 (Box 87, Folder 8)
      - Clippings, [see also SERIES VIII. CLIPPINGS]
        - In support 1948-53 (Box 87, Folder 9)
        - Against 1948-53 (Box 87, Folder 10)
      - Contacts 1948 (Box 87, Folder 11)
      - Correspondence
        - A-B 1948 (Box 87, Folder 12)
        - Bradford, Robert (Governor) 1948-53 (Box 87, Folder 13)
        - C-R 1947-54, undated (Box 87, Folder 14-17)
        - Saltonstall, Leverett (Governor) 1942-48 (Box 87, Folder 18)
        - S-W 1947-48 (Box 87, Folder 19)
        - Wallis, Frank 1947-48 (Box 87, Folder 20)
        - Legislative strategy 1945-46 (Box 87, Folder 21)
      - Financial material 1947-48, undated (Box 87, Folder 22)
      - Legislation
        - House Bill #1748
          - Correspondence 1947-48 (Box 88, Folder 1)
          - Hearings
            - Attendance 1948 (Box 88, Folder 2)
            - Briefs 1948 (Box 88, Folder 3-8)
            - Publicity 1947-48 (Box 88, Folder 9)
            - Schedules and programs 1948 (Box 88, Folder 10)
            - Statements
              - Typescripts 1948 (Box 88, Folder 11)
              - Moral and religious aspects 1948 (Box 88, Folder 12)
              - Social aspects 1948 (Box 88, Folder 13)
              - Majority and minority reports 1947 (Box 88, Folder 14)
          - Initiative petition
            - Information to voters 1948 (Box 89, Folder 1)
            - Memoranda 1947 (Box 89, Folder 2)
            - Signers (original) 1947-48 (Box 89, Folder 3)
      - Laws and legislation
        - Legal advice 1944-49, undated (Box 89, Folder 4)
        - Legislative lists (Massachusetts General Court) 1943-48 (Box 89, Folder 5)
        - Legislators and legislative statistics 1948 (Box 89, Folder 6)
      - Opinions 1940 (Box 89, Folder 7)
      - Opposition 1948 (Box 89, Folder 8)
      - Petition
        - Circulators 1942-48 (Box 89, Folder 9)
        - Records and lists 1948 (Box 89, Folder 10)
      - Petitions 1947 (Box 89, Folder 11)
      - Plans 1945-48 (Box 89, Folder 12)
      - Poster and progress report 1947, [see SERIES IX. OVERSIZE MATERIALS] (Box 89)
      - Publicity and public relations
        - Advertisements 1948, undated (Box 89, Folder 13)
        - Articles, pamphlets, and brochures 1948, undated (Box 89, Folder 14)
        - Press releases 1947-48 (Box 89, Folder 15)
        - Radio 1946-49 (Box 89, Folder 16)
        - Miscellaneous 1948, n.d (Box 89, Folder 17)
      - Resolutions and statements 1948 (Box 90, Folder 1)
      - Signature statistics 1947-48 (Box 90, Folder 2)
      - Signers and signature sheets 1947-48, undated (Box 90, Folder 3)
      - Voting analysis 1948 (Box 90, Folder 4)
      - Voting lists 1948 (Box 90, Folder 5)
      - Voting records
        - County statistics 1947-48 (Box 90, Folder 6-7)
        - Counties
          - Barnstable 1948 (Box 90, Folder 8)
          - Berkshire 1948 (Box 90, Folder 9)
          - Bristol 1948 (Box 90, Folder 10)
          - Dukes 1948 (Box 90, Folder 11)
          - Essex 1948 (Box 90, Folder 12)
          - Franklin 1948 (Box 90, Folder 13)
          - Hampden 1948 (Box 90, Folder 14)
          - Hampshire 1948 (Box 90, Folder 15)
          - Middlesex 1948 (Box 90, Folder 16)
          - Norfolk 1948 (Box 90, Folder 17)
          - Plymouth 1948 (Box 90, Folder 18)
          - Suffolk 1948 (Box 90, Folder 19)
          - Worcester 1948 (Box 90, Folder 20)
        - Voting results 1948 (Box 90, Folder 21)
  - House and Senate bills
    - Committee to Support House Bill 1401
      - Amendment proposed to General Laws, Chapter 272 1965 (Box 91, Folder 1)
      - Bulletin, newsletters, reports, and memos 1965 (Box 91, Folder 2)
      - Financial records
        - Bank statements, checks, and deposit and credit slips 1965 (Box 91, Folder 3)
        - Expenses 1965 (Box 91, Folder 4)
        - Receipts 1965 (Box 91, Folder 5)
        - Petty cash receipts 1965 (Box 91, Folder 6)
        - Taxes and employment forms and correspondence 1965 (Box 91, Folder 7)
      - Legislators 1965 (Box 91, Folder 8)
      - Operation Follow-Through
        - District correspondence 1965 (Box 91, Folder 9)
        - Divisions
          - I-VIII 1965 (Box 91, Folder 10-17)
          - Miscellaneous 1965 (Box 91, Folder 18)
        - Radio (WNAC) program with Cardinal Cushing 1965 (Box 91, Folder 19)
        - Special Commission 1965 (Box 91, Folder 20)
    - House Bills
      - #418
        - Correspondence 1969 (Box 92, Folder 1)
        - Statements 1969 (Box 92, Folder 2)
        - Miscellaneous memos, notes, and reports 1969 (Box 92, Folder 3)
      - #2965
        - Correspondence 1965-66, undated (Box 92, Folder 4)
        - Memos, notes, and legal documents 1966 (Box 92, Folder 5)
        - Statements and lists 1965-66, undated (Box 92, Folder 6)
        - Supporters 1966 (Box 92, Folder 7)
        - Miscellaneous material 1965-69, undated (Box 92, Folder 8)
    - House Special Study Commission Report 1965 (Box 92, Folder 9)
    - Legal documents, lists, and statements 1968-69 (Box 92, Folder 10)
    - Notes (Loraine Campbell) 1965-69 (Box 92, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous legislative materials
    - Correspondence 1962-69 (Box 92, Folder 12)
    - Hearings and opinions 1950-70 (Box 92, Folder 13)
    - Massachusetts General Court members 1948-53 (Box 93, Folder 1)
    - Referendum research 1951-53, undated (Box 93, Folder 2)
    - Resolutions 1964-67 (Box 93, Folder 3)
    - Statements editorials 1953-69 (Box 93, Folder 4)
    - "Unconstitutionality of Massachusetts Birth Control Laws" by Harriet Pilpel (Greenbaum, Wolf and Ernst) 1965 (Box 93, Folder 5)
    - Voting Analysis of Representatives 1966 (Box 93, Folder 6)
  - Connecticut, [see also SERIES IV. RELATED ORGANIZATIONS - Miscellaneous organizations - Planned Parenthood League of Connecticut, SERIES VII. RESOURCE FILES - Countries - United States - Connecticut, and SERIES VIII. CLIPPINGS AND ARTICLES]
    - Articles, clippings, and reprints 1940-66, undated (Box 93, Folder 7)
    - General statutes 1958 (Box 93, Folder 8)
    - History of attempts to legalize birth control 1959, undated (Box 93, Folder 9)
    - House bills, hearings, and miscellaneous attempts to enact new legislation 1943-55 (Box 93, Folder 10)
    - Laws and legislation
      - Cases
        - CT vs. Certain contraceptive materials 1940 (Box 93, Folder 11)
        - Griswold, Buxton vs. CT
          - Correspondence 1959 (Box 93, Folder 12-13)
          - Briefs, motions, and appeals 1964 (Box 93, Folder 14)
        - Nelson, Goodrich, McTernan vs. CT 1940 (Box 93, Folder 15)
        - Tileston vs. Ullman 1942-43 (Box 93, Folder 16)
      - Test cases 1943-59 (Box 93, Folder 17)
- SERIES VII. RESOURCE FILES
  - Abortion 1935-70, undated, [see also SERIES VIII. CLIPPINGS AND ARTICLES] (Box 94, Folder 1)
  - Adoption, [see Countries - U.S.-Tennessee]
    - Birth control, [see also Contraception]
      - Bibliographies 1939-49, undated (Box 94, Folder 2)
      - Education 1940-62, undated (Box 94, Folder 3)
      - History
        - Massachusetts 1929-65 (Box 94, Folder 4)
        - Miscellaneous 1928-68, undated (Box 94, Folder 5)
      - Medical profession 1925-46 (Box 94, Folder 6)
      - Meetings 1937-66, undated (Box 94, Folder 7)
      - Opinions
        - American Medical Association 1937 (Box 94, Folder 8)
        - Physicians 1917-43, undated (Box 94, Folder 9)
        - Miscellaneous 1916-64, undated (Box 94, Folder 10)
      - Policy (U. S. Government) 1962-67 (Box 94, Folder 11)
      - Sterilization 1934-40 (Box 94, Folder 12)
    - Children and adolescents 1935-39 (Box 94, Folder 13)
    - Civil liberties and civil rights 1940-69, undated (Box 94, Folder 14)
    - Clinics 1921-68, undated (Box 94, Folder 15)
    - Contraception 1931-49, [see also Birth Control] (Box 95, Folder 1)
    - Contraceptive methods, [see also Birth Control and SERIES VIII. CLIPPINGS AND ARTICLES]
      - Condoms 1859, undated (Box 95, Folder 2)
      - Pill
        - Research and development 1957-65 (Box 95, Folder 3)
        - Tests (Puerto Rico) 1957-69 (Box 95, Folder 4)
        - Miscellaneous 1952-68, undated (Box 95, Folder 5)
      - Research 1936-62, undated (Box 95, Folder 6)
      - Miscellaneous 1919-70, undated (Box 95, Folder 7)
      - Small box containing rings and condoms (Box 95)
    - Countries
      - Africa
        - Algeria and Egypt 1961-62 (Box 96, Folder 1)
        - Liberia, Mauritius, and Tunisia 1961-62 (Box 96, Folder 2)